( CAR APPROACHING )
( CAR DOOR CLOSES )
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
Hi . I 'm Elise . You must be Lorraine .
Yes . Nice to meet you . I 'm sorry it 's so late .
My day job kind of makes raising my son a night job .
Don 't worry about it .
In my line of work , things tend to happen when it gets dark .
Please . Thank you .
Ahoy , Carl ! ( GASPS )
( CHUCKLES )
Elise , thank you for coming .
I didn 't know what else to do , except call you .
Oh , I understand .
You had a big problem and you thought
you 'd make it my problem , too . Is that it ?
Uh , uh ... ( CHUCKLES )
I 'm teasing .
You know I 'm always happy to help , Carl .
Would you like some coffee or tea ?
No , thank you .
I 'd like to get started right away , if that 's okay .
Carl told me on the phone
your son is the one affected , is that right ?
Yes , that 's right .
My son , Josh .
Something is following him .
Show her .
I started with all the usual checks ,
mental health tests , medical records .
Everything normal .
Then I saw the photos .
First noticed it about six weeks ago .
Thought it was a camera problem .
Then it became apparent that it was more than that .
CARL : I interviewed the boy .
He won 't tell me anything . He 's afraid .
( WHISPERS ) I 'm afraid , too .
There 's something in this house . I can feel it .
It doesn 't want me here .
May I meet him ?
Hi , Josh . I 'm Elise .
I would love to ask you some simple questions .
Do you like living here ?
Yeah , I guess .
Are there a lot of kids your age in this neighborhood ?
A few . One kid lives next door .
That must be fun .
Is there anything you don 't like about living in this house ?
I have bad dreams sometimes .
What happens in your dreams ?
I 'd like to try something with you , Josh .
And I promise , it won 't hurt .
I want you to just relax .
( TICKING )
Listen to the ticking .
Focus on it .
Tune everything else out .
Feel yourself getting sleepier .
We are now inside your dream , Josh .
Look around .
What do you see ?
I see myself
sleeping in bed .
Are you in your bedroom ?
No .
I 'm somewhere dark .
It 's always dark here .
Are you alone ?
No .
She 's here .
ELISE : Who is " she " ?
JOSH : She says she 's a friend .
She visits me every night .
Where is she right at this moment ?
Is she here in this house with us ?
I 'd like to talk to her .
( WHISPERS )
Okay , we 're gonna play a little game , Josh .
It 's called Hot and Cold .
I 'll walk around the house ,
and you tell me if I 'm getting warmer or colder .
Cold .
Warm .
Warmer .
Colder .
( DOOR CREAKING )
Getting warm .
( WHISPERS ) Hotter .
It 's very hot .
Please get out of there .
Who are you ?
What do you want ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( LOUD GROWL ) ( GASPS )
What happened ?
I saw what haunts him , and it 's not a friend .
It 's a parasite . I 've never felt such a malignant presence .
It wants to be him .
Miss Lambert ,
I think your son has a unique ability , a gift .
When he sleeps at night , he 's able to go places , see things .
Things no living person is supposed to see .
Only now , one of the dead has seen him , too .
Oh , my God .
Well , can you stop it ?
I could take away his gift
to suppress his memory of his ability .
How would we do that ?
I 'll show you .
( DOOR CREAKS )
( BOTH GASP )
Do whatever you have to . Make him forget .
( VOICES WHISPERING )
( BABY CRYING )
( DOOR CREAKS )
RENAI : One morning , Dalton just wouldn 't wake up .
We took him to the best doctors we could find ,
but none of them had any idea .
Eventually , we just took him home ,
still in his coma .
Then things started happening around the house .
Unexplained things .
I got so freaked out , we moved .
But they kept happening .
SENDAL : And you believe that there was some sort of supernatural force at work ?
When did you hire the services
of the deceased Elise Rainier ?
When we ran out of places to go .
It says in your statement , Mrs. Lambert ,
that last night , at approximately 10 : 00 p.m. ,
Elise put your husband into a state of hypnosis .
She did this as part of a ritual that
she believed would allow him to
" project his unconscious into a ... " Uh ...
I 'm sorry , I can 't read my own handwriting .
" ... into a spirit realm , where he could locate your son "
" and bring him back to consciousness . "
Now , did you really believe that would help ?
I had to . Whatever she did , it worked .
Dalton woke up .
And what happened after your son woke up ?
RENAI : Josh !
Josh , where are you ?
Josh !
( GASPING )
( WHIMPERS )
( GASPS )
JOSH : Renai .
I 'm right here . ( GASPS )
What ? Renai .
( STUTTERS )
Oh , no , no , no .
Elise ! Elise !
Mom , get Dalton out of here ! Call an ambulance !
No , no , no . Elise !
Oh , no !
No , no !
What ?
Why are you looking at me like that ?
You think I did this ?
Did you believe him ?
He 's my husband . That 's not what I asked .
Yes , I believed him . My husband isn 't capable of killing anybody .
This is a photo Elise took seconds before she was killed .
Can you tell me who that is in this picture ?
There were a lot of strange things happening in our house .
I saw apparitions , lots of them .
Are you telling me that this is a photograph of a ghost ?
Listen , I 'm not interested in ghosts , Mrs. Lambert .
I 'm interested in the living people who create them .
Elise has marks on her neck
that were put there by human hands .
I 'll let you know if forensics matches those marks to your husband .
LORRAINE : Jessica , we 're home .
JESSICA : Hey , guys .
Dad ! Look what I made . Hey .
What ? It 's a cup phone .
See ? You put your ear in that , and I put my mouth in that .
You are a genius . Absolute brilliance . Thanks for watching them .
LORRAINE : Say hi to your mom from me . I will .
Oh . Mom , I 'll get that .
LORRAINE : I 'll go up and make the beds .
( TODDLER WALKER MUSIC PLAYING )
( COOING )
( THUD )
( KALI CRYING )
JOSH : All right . ( DOOR OPENS )
Time for bed , boys .
How long are we gonna be here for ?
We 're gonna be at Grandma 's house for a little bit
while the police work at our house .
You know , this house has been in the family for a long time .
And you guys
get to stay in Daddy 's old bedroom .
Did you see anything bad in here ?
No .
And neither will you , okay ?
Okay .
Good night .
What ?
Just glad you 're awake .
Good night , boys .
FOSTER : Good night .
Hey , Dalton .
What ?
Look what I made .
Do I have to ?
Yeah .
This is stupid .
Come on , it really works . I wanna ask you something , all right ?
All right , fine . The string needs to be tight .
Go farther back . Okay .
So , what do you think of this ?
I think it 's stupid .
Hey .
( EXHALES )
( PIANO PLAYING FAINTLY )
Lorraine ?
( MUSIC STOPS )
( CONTINUES PLAYING )
( SWITCHES OFF RADIO )
( KALI CRYING )
( PIANO PLAYING )
( CONTINUES PLAYING )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( TODDLER WALKER MUSIC PLAYING )
( KALI CRYING OVER BABY MONITOR )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( KALI CONTINUES CRYING )
( STOPS CRYING ABRUPTLY )
( KALI WAILING )
It 's okay .
( DOOR OPENS )
It 's still happening . What is ?
I heard the piano playing by itself downstairs
and I found Kali on the floor of her room by her crib !
Well , maybe she climbed out of her crib .
Has she ever done that before ?
What ? What is wrong with you ?
Renai , I just want us to move on from this , that 's all .
I want us to be a normal family again .
There is nothing normal about this , okay ? These things are still here .
Elise is dead ! No one 's talking about it ! Someone murdered her !
Then let 's talk about it .
You think I did it ?
No . No , I don 't .
Good . Good .
Because I know what happened .
I went into that place to get our son back
and something evil followed me and killed Elise .
You saw it .
You saw those things .
Listen to me . Nothing is gonna bother us , not anymore .
We have our family back .
We have our son .
Isn 't that what we should be focusing on ?
Yeah .
( DOG BARKING )
( GATE CLOSES )
( DOOR CLOSES )
You think all the ghosts we 've seen
would somehow make me feel better that Elise is gone .
I mean , you and I have
firsthand knowledge that there 's something out there beyond death .
But it 's not helping .
Turns out the living version of someone is always better .
( DOOR OPENS )
( DOOR CREAKING )
( CREAKING CONTINUES )
She never left the reading room unlocked .
You first .
Hunter , ninja , bear .
BOTH : Hunter , ninja , bear .
That 's bullshit .
( EXHALES )
How does a bear beat a goddamn ninja ?
SPECS : Superior sense of smell , my friend .
You know what ? I don 't think we should be down here .
Let 's go back .
That 's a private room . You should stay ...
See ? Oh , my nuts !
I 'm not helping .
( GRUNTS )
Hi , Josh . I 'm Elise .
Hey .
I would love to ask you some simple questions .
But they 're the good kind , the kind you can 't get wrong .
Do you like living here ?
JOSH : Yeah .
Amateur framing . Just horrible .
( BOTH SHUSHING )
A few . One kid lives next door .
( REWINDING )
LORRAINE : Can you stop it ?
ELISE : I could try to take away his gift
to suppress his memory of his ability .
LORRAINE : How would we do that ?
I 'll show you .
( REWINDING )
Who the hell 's he talking to ?
ELISE : I could try to take away his gift ,
to suppress his memory of his ability .
LORRAINE : How would we do that ?
I 'll show you .
Right there .
( TV PLAYING )
sleep . Then I flew away .
( WHISPERS ) Please don 't leave us again .
Grandma ?
Mmm-hmm .
There 's someone standing behind you .
( MUSIC PLAYING FAINTLY )
( TODDLER WALKER MUSIC PLAYING LOUDLY )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Renai ?
( WIND HOWLING )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( GASPS )
Oh , my God , Josh ! Mom !
Did you see her ? I saw someone !
No , you didn 't . No , I did ! There was somebody ...
Ma , there is no one here , okay ?
Because if there was , that would scare my family ,
and I don 't need Renai hearing any of that stuff right now .
Understand ?
Yeah , you 're right . Um ...
It was probably my imagination .
Yeah .
Sorry . You should get some sleep .
( EXHALES )
( TV PLAYING )
You want some more ?
( FOSTER TALKING INDISTINCTLY )
FOSTER : All right , go farther back so we can stretch it . We need to make it tight .
Daddy ?
I gotcha ! I gotcha ! Oh , my God !
I 'm going to eat you .
DALTON : Mom ?
Hey , honey , what do you want for breakfast ?
Anything you want .
I don 't care .
What 's wrong ?
What 's the matter ? You can tell me .
I had a bad dream .
Okay .
I 'm sorry . What was it about ?
I was in my bed sleeping .
Grandma walked in .
I could see someone else in my room .
Please don 't leave us again .
Grandma ?
Mmm-hmm .
There 's someone standing behind you .
I tried to wake myself up .
It took a while , but I did it .
I heard voices in the hallway .
You got to go .
You have to go .
It was Daddy .
You have to leave .
And he was talking to someone .
You have to go .
Is there something wrong with Daddy , Mom ?
No .
No , honey .
He 's just been through a lot .
That 's all . We all have .
It 's okay , it 's just a dream .
I 'm gonna take the boys to school .
You should rest , relax a bit .
Come on , son .
Okay .
SPECS : Are you okay , Lorraine ?
You said something was wrong .
Whatever it was that killed Elise ,
whatever it was that was haunting my family
is not done with us .
Last night I saw someone in my house .
I need your help .
SPECS : Do you remember the first time Elise visited your house
to talk to Josh when he was a boy ?
No . I did a lot to try to ...
Try to forget that part of my life , until recently .
All right . Well , Elise hypnotized him ,
asked him a series of questions .
I digitized the actual footage taken from the night .
I cropped and lightened the image .
What ?
SPECS : Lorraine , is that Josh ?
How is that possible ?
SPECS : We don 't know .
If only Elise were here to help us .
What ?
( LIGHT FLICKERING )
( PHONE RINGING )
( CONTINUES RINGING )
Hello ?
Renai Lambert , this is Detective Sendal .
Oh .
Hello , Detective .
I told you I would inform you once I got the forensics results .
Well , I got some .
It seems the bruises on Elise Rainier 's neck
do not match your husband 's hands .
We 're not ruling anything out at this point ,
but I just thought you should know .
Thank you , Detective . Uh ...
I really needed to hear that . ( CHUCKLES ) Thank you .
( SIGHS )
( TODDLER WALKER MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUSIC STOPS )
♪ Row , row , row your boat ♪
♪ Gently down the stream ♪
( OVER BABY MONITOR ) ♪ Merrily , merrily , merrily , merrily ♪
♪ Life is but a dream ♪
( KALI CRYING )
Kali ?
Kali , what 's wrong ?
( WHIMPERS )
Kali ! Kali !
FEMALE VOICE : What a beautiful little girl .
Don 't you dare !
( SLAPS ) ( KALI WAILING )
Jesus !
Oh , my God . Oh , my God !
( MUMBLING )
( KALI CRYING )
( WHIMPERS )
Kali !
( SCREAMING )
Kali ? Baby ?
( WHIMPERING ) My baby , Kali . Kali .
Don 't you dare !
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
He 's here .
Carl , I 'm Specs . I 'm the guy you spoke to on the phone .
Oh , hello ! Come in .
Hi , Carl . Oh .
It 's been a long time .
Yeah .
( SIGHS ) Looks like I did the aging for the both of us .
Oh , please stop it .
You met Specs . This is Tucker .
Elise talked about you a lot .
Oh . Yeah , said you were the second best person
she ever worked with .
Second best , that 's generous .
I had been meaning to catch up with her , to call her .
But I always kept putting it off till the next week , you know ?
And now she 's gone .
Well , maybe this is your chance to say your good-byes .
Specs told me on the phone , but I 'm not sure we should ...
We have questions that need answering ,
and the only person we could think of to ask is Elise .
Please help us , Carl .
Help us contact her .
CARL : Everybody has their own way of making contact .
This is mine .
I ask questions and the spirits answer with the dice .
You look for the words in the letters .
Elise , we are calling out to you .
Tell us if you are there .
Elise , please talk to us .
Give us a sign that you can hear my voice .
All right , I suppose I should 've explained
that this isn 't an exact science .
Sometimes contact can 't be made .
Elise .
Please tell me , are you here ?
Are you here ?
I 'll go get ... No !
Do not break the circle .
Elise .
We need to know who killed you .
Tell us .
" She did . "
( GASPS )
( CEILING LAMP CREAKING )
What does she want ?
I see it .
Where ?
" K-I-L-L . "
Where is she ?
SPECS : " Hiding . "
( VOICES WHISPERING ) CARL : Where is she hiding ?
( GARBLED VOICES )
( WIND HOWLING )
Elise , tell us where to find your killer .
" Our Lady Angls " ?
( STUTTERS ) Our Lady Angls , what does that mean ?
It 's " Angels . "
Our Lady of the Angels .
It 's a hospital .
I know because I used to work there .
Renai ?
( SIGHS )
Renai .
( SNIFFS )
LORRAINE : Most of my work was in this East Wing .
But it 's all closed now .
Now only the ghosts are left .
CARL : ( WHISPERS ) Personally , I prefer the ghosts to people .
LORRAINE : The question is , what are we looking for ?
Elise led us here for a reason .
Just forget the actual building .
Think of the doctors , the nurses you worked with ,
the patients , everyone .
DOLL : Mama ! Mama !
What is it ?
( WHIMPERING )
( LAUGHS )
In there .
CARL : What was in this room ?
This was an ICU .
I remember it very well .
Should we do pizza night tonight ?
How about mac and cheese ?
Hi , Pam . Hi , Lorraine .
Mac and cheese .
Okay , that can be done .
Keep quiet . Don 't touch anything .
How is he ?
His vital signs are stabilizing ,
but he 's still unresponsive .
LORRAINE : His blood pressure 's doing better .
NURSE : Yes , after we upped the dosage .
LORRAINE : Okay , let 's keep him on that . NURSE : Okay .
LORRAINE : And when was the last time you checked the glucose ?
( BEEPING )
( SCREAMS )
( LORRAINE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
It 's okay . It 's okay .
LORRAINE : A few days later , I saw him again .
For the last time .
( ELEVATOR DINGS )
( SIGHS )
Parker , what are you ...
You should be resting . You shouldn 't be out of bed .
Listen , I wanna apologize for my son the other day .
He was being a nosy kid .
( ELEVATOR DINGS )
Hey , Hillary , why is the patient from Room 104
up and walking around ?
What do you mean ?
The patient from ICU , Parker Crane ?
What do you mean , walking around ?
I just rode down in the elevator with him .
He should be in bed , on the monitor ...
Lorraine , that patient died yesterday morning .
What ?
He jumped to his death .
( GASPS )
CARL : So , why was he here in the first place ?
He tried to castrate himself .
( SCREAMS )
( GASPS )
Oh , no .
No .
No , not yet .
Please , no .
FEMALE VOICE : Your dead soul is killing his living skin .
I wanna live .
I wanna live !
Only if you kill them .
( SOBBING ) No . Please , no .
I can 't , Mother .
Please don 't make me do it .
You must !
Or you 'll waste away .
Yes , we can .
No way . Lorraine !
TUCKER : Is that our man ?
LORRAINE : Parker Crane , that 's him .
CARL : This address , there 's something there .
( SCREAMING )
It 's okay , it 's okay . Renai . ( SHUSHING )
It 's okay . It 's okay . You 're okay . You 're okay .
Oh , God . You 're okay .
Where 's Kali ?
She 's fine . She 's in her room sleeping .
She 's fine . No , she 's not ! No , she 's not !
She 's asleep ! Renai ! No ! No !
Kali .
( KALI COOING )
See ? I told you , she 's fine .
Oh , God ! What happened ? Tell me .
Someone attacked me !
Who ?
In the living room , a woman . She hit me . These things are back , Josh !
We have to go ! We gotta get the kids
and we gotta get out of the house !
No , it 's not the house . You know that .
We 've been through this before .
They will follow us . You have to just not be afraid .
You have to relax .
Relax ? I can 't relax !
There 's ghosts everywhere !
It 's like we 're already dead !
No , it 's not !
No , it 's not .
This is nothing like being dead .
I know . I have seen it .
I have seen where these things exist .
They want what you have .
Life .
But they have no power over you .
All you have to do is ignore them , and they will go away .
( PIANO PLAYING FAINTLY )
( CONTINUES PLAYING )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( DOOR CREAKS )
See , I told you .
( PLAYING PIANO )
( SINGING MELODY )
What are you doing ?
( STOPS PLAYING )
That 's the song that 's been playing .
What song ? What are you talking about ?
You mm know that song ?
No , I don 't .
That 's my song , the song I wrote for you ?
Well , it 's not the song that we should be worried about .
There 's somebody in this house .
Stay here .
Hey , look , they left the window open .
TUCKER : Watch your step .
Do you feel something ?
Um ...
Let 's just say that this house is not a place
where many good things have happened .
Probably a lot of good collectibles in here .
( LORRAINE COUGHS )
( CONTINUE COUGHING )
( SNIFFING )
What is that smell ?
TUCKER : Hey , Specs .
SPECS : Yeah .
Upstairs .
( BANGS )
( KICKS )
I 'm guessing this might be Parker Crane 's bedroom .
SPECS : No , it seems a little girly for a boy 's bedroom ,
don 't you think ?
Why ?
I mean , look at this dollhouse .
What ?
I had a dollhouse .
This is a Rhode Island Red .
Come on , let 's get outta here .
GIRL : This is my room !
( SPECS GASPING )
Tucker !
( WHIMPERING )
( WOOD CREAKING )
( GASPS )
Listen , Tucker . Tucker .
( WHISPERS ) You can 't be in here .
If she sees you , she 'll make me kill you .
FEMALE VOICE : ( OVER CUP PHONE ) Dalton .
Dalton .
( SIGHS )
What ?
I have something to show you .
Stop , Foster .
Just go back to bed . You 're gonna get us in trouble .
I 'm not Foster .
( GASPS )
Foster , wake up .
Foster , please wake up !
( DOOR CREAKS )
Who are you ?
The ones he killed .
We are many .
What do you want ?
Please help me !
( INAUDIBLE )
Make the pain stop !
( SCREAMING )
( GASPS )
( ALL SCREAMING )
( DALTON SCREAMING )
It 's okay ! It 's okay ! It 's okay ! ( SOBBING )
It 's okay ! It 's okay ! It 's okay !
Oh , Jesus . Jesus . Oh , Jesus .
It 's okay . It 's okay . It 's okay .
It was just a dream . It 's just a dream .
It 's just a dream .
You 're trying to reach her , but you won 't .
Not from over there .
Shadows are your home now .
Help !
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Elise .
Why did you bring us here ?
What are we looking for ?
( SQUEAKING )
" Mors . "
Latin for " Death " ?
Carl .
This is the woman who was in my house .
( CLATTERS )
Lorraine , look out !
( PANTING ) What happened ?
( PANTING )
What happened ? Give me a light over here .
Over here !
You 're not Elise , are you ?
( GASPS )
( LOUD THUD )
( WHIMPERS )
Who are you ?
Mother of Death .
What does that mean ?
It 's literal .
It simply means the mother
of Parker Crane .
( OBJECT CREAKING )
( RIPPING )
( SILENCE )
( CREAKING )
( TAPPING )
( THUDDING )
( KNOCKS )
( LOUD THUD ) ( GASPS LOUDLY )
( SHUSHES )
Okay , move that .
( STRAINING ) One , two , and three .
( BOTH GRUNTING )
TUCKER : Pull it this way .
( ALL GAGGING )
( ALL COUGHING )
( GAGGING )
TUCKER : Don 't touch anything .
Guys .
" Bride in Black . "
I know that name .
TUCKER : Where ? What you got ?
" SPECS : " One of the victims managed to elude the killer .
" Police said she described her attacker "
" as an old woman dressed in a black wedding gown and veil . "
" Bride in Black claims his 15th victim . "
Victims .
CARL : Oh , my God .
Wait a sec .
Uh ...
( MUFFLED SCREAM )
( SHRIEKS )
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
Parker wore that dress
to commit these murders .
It was his disguise .
He killed for his mother because she forced him to .
He wanted his childhood back .
That 's why he went after your son .
Renai ! Jesus ! Lorraine !
Where have you been ?
I need to speak to you .
Where is he , Josh ?
He 's not feeling well . He 's been in bed all day .
And where are Dalton and Foster ?
I just dropped them off at Jessica 's .
Why ? You and the kids are in danger .
I 'll explain , but not here .
Please , let 's just get in the car and go .
Have you been seeing them , too ?
Around the house ?
It 's not the house , it 's Josh .
( CAR ENGINE STARTING )
They 're gone . It 's go time .
Okay . We 'll hear everything .
Sing out if you need us .
The code word is " Quesadilla . "
Say it with me . Quesadilla . " Quesadilla . "
I thought we agreed on " Unicorn " as the code word .
Uh ... " Quesadilla " is easier to bring up in conversation .
Not at all . How would you bring up
" quesadilla " in a conversation ?
It 's lunch time . It 's quesadilla time . Guys , guys , guys , guys .
I 'd love a quesadilla . Can I have a quesadilla ?
Really ?
I don 't think it matters .
You 'll know if I need you . It doesn 't matter .
Tranquilizer .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
Can I help you ?
My name 's Carl .
Uh , I know you don 't remember me , Josh .
Elise and I did our best to make sure of that .
You 're right , I don 't remember you .
Your mother called me when you started experiencing some problems
and what I saw scared me so badly that I , uh , reached out to Elise .
Now Elise is gone .
I was wondering if you could help give me some closure .
I need it .
Sure .
Okay .
( CARL CLEARS THROAT )
Phew !
This is pretty exciting .
I feel like an FBI agent .
Tell me what you 're thinking . Lorraine , what do you know ?
I think that when Josh went into that other world ,
something else came back .
We believe it 's a spirit that 's killed
many times before , and it 'll kill again .
That 's why I had to get you and the kids away from him .
Last night , when I looked into his eyes ,
like I have every day for the last 12 years ,
was the first time I didn 't recognize him .
I was scared of him .
Right now , at the house ,
there is an acquaintance of Elise 's and mine , and he 's talking to Josh .
We 're going to try to sedate him and when he 's under ,
we 're going to try to reach out to the real Josh .
And what if we can 't find him ?
( JOSH COUGHING )
( STUTTERS ) Are you feeling okay ?
I 'm fine .
Just woke up feeling a little under the weather .
I suppose I wanted to ask you
if you 've any idea what happened to Elise .
No , I don 't .
Look , I ...
I should remind you that , um ...
I 'm not the person who 's gonna look at you funny
if you tell me something unusual .
Mmm-hmm .
I 've seen things with my own eyes
that most people have to go to sleep to conjure up .
Elise sent me to a place that still haunts my dreams .
But I got my son back .
I don 't know , I left the room for about 10 minutes ,
and when I came back , Elise was dead .
She had been strangled .
That 's pretty horrific .
I guess .
Oh !
Um ...
When you were a boy ,
you said it was an old woman who haunted you .
Did you see that same old woman
when you were in that other world ?
No .
Okay . Um ...
Say , would you like a drink ?
( STAMMERS )
Water . A glass of water would be nice .
Sure .
What you got there ?
Huh ? Oh . Uh ...
Nothing .
I thought maybe you were playing with your dice .
Excuse me ?
Mother tells me you like to play with dice .
Did she ? I didn 't realize you guys had spoken this morning .
It 's how I do my readings .
Ah .
What have you got behind your back ?
Why don 't you ask your dice what I have behind my back ?
Come on , roll them and see .
Mother tells me you were very good with them at the house .
Come on , it 'll be fun .
What ...
What does Josh ...
What is Parker Crane holding behind his back ?
She was always right .
BOTH : Shit !
( YELLS )
CARL : Ah !
Come on !
( YELLS )
( STRAINING )
( CHOKING )
Quesadilla .
Carl ! CARL : In here !
I got you !
( GRUNTS )
( GROANING )
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTS )
I know you , don 't I ?
Well , if you 're here , I guess I don 't have to ask where I am .
( GHOSTLY SCREAMS )
He killed you .
I 'm sorry .
That thing is gonna murder my family if I don 't get back .
I am trapped here . I 'm getting weaker
the longer I 'm away from my body .
( SIGHS )
Elise .
Elise , she 's not here .
Well , then we 'll have to find her .
( DOOR CREAKS )
Into the Further we go .
FEMALE VOICE : You need to kill the others .
It 's the only way to stay alive .
Shut up ! Shut up ! Get out of my head !
Shut up ! Get outta here !
Get out of my head !
( CELL PHONE VIBRATING )
Okay , I 've just got a message from Tucker . He says they 're ready .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
" JOSH " . Elise ?
( GHOSTLY VOICES WHISPERING )
CARL : Elise !
( GHOSTLY SCREAMS )
Don 't do that .
What is it ?
There 's someone standing in front of you .
I don 't see anybody .
CARL : He 's right in front of you !
He 's ...
He 's talking to you .
What 's he saying ?
CARL : " He 's got your baby . "
" He 's got your baby . He 's got your baby . He 's got your baby . "
He 's got your baby . He 's got your baby .
What 's he doing now ?
He ...
He 's pointing at something .
Over there .
RENAI : I heard this noise coming from Kali 's room-It was on the baby monitor .
JOSH : Probably just interference .
RENAI : I don 't know .
It sounded so clear . It was like this whispering . It was ...
Scared the hell out of me .
RENAI : Then I went to hear the monitor and turned up the volume
and heard a man 's voice .
I ran up there and I looked inside .
JOSH : Probably just some noise . Those things always pick up ...
( GASPING )
( KALI CRYING OVER BABY MONITOR )
No ! No ! No . ( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( PANTING ) No ! Hey !
( BANGING ON DOOR )
Who the hell is that ?
Hold on .
Stay here .
Renai !
( GASPS )
Hello ?
No . Josh , no !
( KALI CRYING OVER BABY MONITOR )
Josh ! Josh ! Quick ! There 's someone in here ! Someone in the curtains !
( CONTINUES CRYING )
CARL : Josh ! Josh !
Renai !
( BANGS ON DOOR )
( ALARM BLARING )
( RENAI SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
Renai !
JOSH : Get away from her ! ( GROWLS )
Get away from her !
( GRUNTING )
( SCREAMS )
ELSIE : GO to hell !
Josh . ( SIGHS )
I wish I could say it 's good to see you .
I 'm so sorry .
You shouldn 't be here .
We all pass through this place eventually .
Hopefully , on our way to someplace better .
( SIGHS ) I 've seen that better place ,
but I came back here because I heard you calling ,
and I think I can help .
Carl , what are you doing here ?
You are not supposed to be here .
I failed you , Elise .
Oh ...
No , you didn 't . No , you didn 't .
You were looking for Josh and you found him .
Josh , you don 't belong here ,
and neither does that entity belong in your world .
I don 't know how to fight her .
Out there in the darkness ,
she has a home where all her memories live from her life .
Use those memories to draw her out of your vessel
so that you can get back into your body .
But where do I find her home ?
Only you know where that is .
( SIGHS )
I don 't remember .
Maybe we 're asking the wrong Josh .
What happened ?
I saw what haunts him , and it 's not a friend . It 's a parasite .
I 've never felt such a malignant presence .
It wants to be him .
Miss Lambert , I think your son has a unique ability , a gift .
Josh .
I need your help .
I don 't have any memories of the old woman anymore ,
but you do .
I need to know where she lives .
I 'll show you .
( GASPS )
So that 's what that was about .
( DOOR CREAKING )
Carl ?
( OBJECT CREAKING )
Josh ?
Hi , honey . ( CLEARS THROAT )
I 'm waiting for the boys . They 're not home yet .
Did my friend Carl stop by today ?
No , I don 't think so .
( BOTH SCREAMING )
You did this to yourselves !
( SCREAMING )
( CHUCKLING )
It 's been so long since I felt real pain .
Renai , help me !
I missed it , but not as much as I miss inflicting it on others .
( SCREAMS )
( WHIMPERS )
( GRUNTING )
( EXCLAIMS )
Renai , get out of here ! Run !
I 'll come back for you , Mommy !
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTING )
( GRUNTS )
( GROANING )
JESSICA : Okay , guys , we 're here . FOSTER : Yay !
DALTON : Thanks , Jessica .
FOSTER : Thank you .
JESSICA : No problem . See you tomorrow .
DALTON : Let 's go , Foster .
( GROANING )
I didn 't want this , Renai .
She wanted me to kill you , but I said no .
But now , I know she was right .
( GASPING )
( GRUNTS ) ( SCREAMS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
You are a miserable , ungrateful bitch .
You have no idea how much you 've wasted
your life being afraid of the dead ,
because pretty soon , you 're going to be one of them .
Then , when I take you to my home in the dark ,
you 'll realize how happy you should 've been
for your brief , little moment in the sun .
( CHOKING )
( EXHALES )
( WHEEZING )
( CHUCKLES )
( SCREAMS )
Mommy ! Mommy !
( SCREAMS ) Daddy ! No !
( RENAI WHIMPERING )
( YELLS )
( BANGING ON DOOR )
Come on !
( BOYS WHIMPERING )
( YELLING )
( THUDDING )
( PANTING )
Hello ?
My name is Parker !
What is this ?
Did you do this ?
Don 't you dare !
But , Mommy ...
Speak the truth .
Did you ?
( WHIMPERING )
Yes . That is not your name !
Parker is not your name !
That is the name your father gave you !
Your name
is Marilyn .
Do you understand ?
Repeat after me .
" My name is Marilyn . "
Say it !
My name is ...
Marilyn .
Quiet , now .
If you don 't be a good little girl , you 'll get ...
( GROWLING )
Mommy , Mommy , I can go into the dark place
and find Daddy , if I go to sleep .
No , it 's too dangerous .
I nearly lost you once before .
I 'm not gonna let that happen again .
I can find him . I promise I 'll find him . I promise .
I will .
Turn around .
( LOUD THUDDING )
( WHIMPERING ) It 's okay !
Be careful .
I love you .
Destroy her , Josh ! End this !
FEMALE VOICE : Where am I ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( FEMALE VOICE LAUGHING )
( WHIMPERS )
( GRUNTS )
( GASPS )
( LOUD FOOTSTEPS )
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTING )
( GROANS )
( EXCLAIMS )
Let her go !
Lorraine ?
Where is he ? He ...
He 's got Renai .
What the hell !
( GROANS )
( GRUNTING )
( WHIMPERING )
( GROANS )
( PANTING )
Parker , help me destroy the memories of her .
It will set you free .
Please let me in .
Open the door .
( GRUNTS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SCREAMS )
( GRUNTS )
Little girls need to learn to be good !
( GROWLS )
No !
( GROANS )
( GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
Baby !
Hey !
RENAI : Hey , come back ! Come back !
( COUGHING )
Elise !
Josh , go now .
I wish I could take you with me .
I can 't . But you can take Carl .
What ?
I told you , you don 't belong here .
I felt your heartbeat when I hugged you .
You 're still alive . It 's time to live again .
But you both have to go now !
Go now !
Go !
( GHOSTLY WHISPERS )
( SPIRITS SCREAMING )
( JOSH GASPS )
Get away !
( SPIRITS SNARLING )
JOSH : Get back ! Get back !
DALTON : Daddy !
( GASPING ) Dalton ?
Dalton !
DALTON : Daddy !
( JOSH STUTTERS )
Where are you , son ?
Daddy !
Oh !
Oh , good boy ! What are you doing here ?
I came to bring you home !
How did you find me ?
I followed your steps .
RENAI : Please wake up !
Where are you ? Come back , come on !
Come back to me .
That 's Mommy .
Wake up !
Get back to me !
CARL : Clever boy . Follow me .
Wake up .
Come on , wake up !
( COUGHING )
( GASPING )
( PANTING )
( GROANING )
( GASPS )
It 's me .
Renai , it 's me , it 's okay .
It 's okay .
Daddy ?
Yeah .
Daddy , you 're back !
Thanks to you .
My boys . Hey , buddy .
Renai , it 's me , it 's okay .
I tried reaching you . I tried everything . ( STUTTERS )
I played your song .
I should 've known it was you .
Only you could play it that badly .
( BOTH LAUGH )
( EXCLAIMING )
( SCREAMING )
Bring it !
( SIGHS )
Are you ready ?
We 're ready .
Ready to forget once and for all .
No more traveling , right ?
This is the only world we wanna be in .
Good , Mr. Lambert .
So then , close your eyes .
Both of you .
Now take a deep breath ,
and just listen to the ticking .
Now feel yourselves getting sleepier and sleepier ,
and let the darkness drift further
and further away .
BRIAN : Who is it ? I have a message for you .
It 's about Allison .
Is this some kind of joke ?
We have a close personal friend who has , uh ,
spoken with Allison .
That 's not possible .
You better leave now or I 'm calling the police .
Wait , Brian .
Who are you guys ?
Uh ... We help people , ma 'am .
People who 've been afflicted by ... Who 's the lady ?
What lady , honey ?
The lady standing behind them .
( SHUSHES )
Um ...
SPECS : Our friend told us to tell you
that Allison 's accident was no accident .
When she was resuscitated back to life at the hospital ,
she brought something back with her .
TUCKER : Not just one thing , many things .
And they 're living here in this house with you .
Allison .
( WOOD CREAKING )
( CREAKING )
( GASPS )
Oh , my God !